<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (advice)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Recover quick!</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/recover-quick.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quarter finals, Bangalore: We barely made into, and were elated about being
in. Its the first half and we catch-up to 4-5 after we were trailing by a
bigger margin. After some good defense, we are on O, and we make some nice
moves to move up to the end zone, and I ask for a disc that I didn't really
have. A man is on me, but the disc reaches before him, and I put it down, in
the endzone!  The game went on; my team wasn't mad at me and continued playing
hard, but we lost the game 8-9.  The catch was a crucial one, that I think
cost us the game.  I sat out for most of the rest of the game.  Others covered
for me, even when we had a really tiny squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody makes mistakes.  Great players, included.  But, what makes them
great is that they put their mistakes behind them very quickly, atleast in the
short term and move on.  I think I've seen some of the players, even let their
mistakes push them into "the zone", performing a few notches above what they
were, before they made that silly drop or made that wild throw.  Like its
important to recover physically, in as short time as possible to be a good
player/athlete (we can talk about that in another post, someday), its also
important to atleast get over your mistakes in the short term (if not be
motivated, by them) and continue to play for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Son, you dropped a simple catch?  This is your chance for that psycho layout
D!  Err, but recoverr...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of interesting blog posts by Jason, on this topic: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ultimaterob.com/2012/09/06/ultimate-intelligence-the-good-mistakes/"&gt;Good Mistakes&lt;/a&gt;
, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ultimaterob.com/2013/01/23/ultimate-intelligence-its-not-about-you/"&gt;It's not about you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mental-game</category><category>recovery</category><category>team</category><category>advice</category><category>mistake</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/recover-quick.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 18:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Good players -- A quote</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/good-players.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's a lovely quote from the preface of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://books.google.co.in/books?id=Zvgbmv7OinAC&amp;amp;pg=PR9&amp;amp;lpg=PR9"&gt;Ultimate - Techniques &amp;amp; Tactics&lt;/a&gt; by James
Parinella and Eric Zaslow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Resolve yourself to becoming a good player. Good players chase down swill.
Good players clear out.  Good players cut when they're tired. Good players
remember the defense. Good players call for help when they need it. In
fact, "good" players are great players. Great teams also require great
teammates. Become a great teammate. Be ready to play on time. Critique but
don't criticize your teammates. Apologize for your mistakes. Take yourself
out of the game when you're tired. Eschew pride.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>good</category><category>how-to</category><category>improve</category><category>advice</category><category>tips</category><category>quote</category><category>player</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/good-players.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>If you touch it, you should catch it.</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/if-you-touch-it-you-should-catch-it.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a random post on getting better at catching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday's game: Light vs. Dark.  Score-line: 2-11 &amp;amp; 2-4.  A very
lopsided game.  For the record, I was in the light/white team.  What
went wrong?  A lot of things, we were getting a lot of our basics
wrong and the opposition was capitalizing on every small mistake we
made.  We were getting broken, left, right and center; Getting beaten
on the open side; and worst of all dropping simple catches -- unforced
turnovers!  I'm guilty of a couple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the opposition was running hard in D and putting a lot of
pressure on us, but most of the catches that were dropped, seemed to
me like the players were thinking of where they'll put the disc next,
even before they got the disc in their hands.  Like they say, you
should be watching the disc into your hands, while catching it.  Set
yourself, look around and put it, where you want to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the things, I think would help avoid silly drops --&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch the disc into your hands, and catch it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't begin to think of your throw, before the catch.  Worse, don't
let yourself think about the fight you had with your boyfriend on
the previous night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get comfortable with having the disc in your hands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even if you are just a cutter, develop a reasonable arsenal of
throws, so you feel more comfortable getting the disc into your
hands and passing it onto the handler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lot more tips in this issue of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.the-huddle.org/issues/8/anticipation-and-focus/"&gt;the huddle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If you touch it, you should catch it." -- Bill Burruss&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>catch</category><category>disc</category><category>advice</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/if-you-touch-it-you-should-catch-it.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 03:05:03 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>