<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (defense)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Marking: Positioning and Distance</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/marking-positioning-and-distance.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;During Hyderabad HAT, I was in the cup for most part and learnt a few
things about marking.  My marking improved slightly during the
tournament, and all it needed was changing a couple of simple things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="distance-from-the-handler"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Distance from the handler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was getting broken left, right and center on zone offense.  I know
that I don't move as quickly as I should, to prevent a dump to the
handler on the break side.  But, thanks to help from Vrajesh, I
realized it's not all about speed.  I was getting broken too easily,
because I'd stand too close to the handler and stepping around me was
very easy.  Standing back a couple of steps, helped me.  I was
struggling with this initially, but Vrajesh helped me with this on the
side lines, asking me to step back a little, each time he saw me
stepping too close, and soon I was able to judge the distance myself
and adjust.  Stepping back made it harder for the handler to step
around me and dump, leading to far fewer breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="running-to-your-wo-man-handler"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Running to your (wo)man (handler)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it's a pull, and you are running
down from the other end-zone, it helps if you run down on the break
side, instead of running straight up.  Position yourself a little on
the breakside, so that you don't give away easy break side throws.  If
you are in a cup (or even otherwise), when you run to your (wo)man
(from the force side), don't slow down as soon you reach within the
marking range (3 yards) of your (wo)man. Start slowing down, only once
you cross your man and get to the break side a little and try to stop
as quickly as possible.  That way you are disallowing any easy
breakside throws, just by getting in the way of the throw, even if you
are in no position to "really mark".  Then move in, and position
yourself at the appropriate distance, angle and what not...  Look at
the image below to see, what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/marking.png" src="http://blog.ultimatesport.in/images/marking.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>position</category><category>defense</category><category>tips</category><category>mark</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/marking-positioning-and-distance.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Catch Your D's</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/catch-your-ds.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Tuesday's match, I got a couple of good D's, or so I thought, until
I saw that the discs that I smacked away, didn't actually go crashing
into the ground, but instead just slowed down and became easy catches
for the guys that I D-ed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the discs were "catchable", and I think I should've caught them.
To make sure that your disc crashes right into the ground, you need to
time your smack, and direct it correctly, and make sure you've enough
power in your smack; and you already trying to time your jump, to get
to the disc before your opponent!  Adding one more level of complexity
doesn't really help, does it?  Catching is something we are practicing
all the time, and when the disc is catchable, I think it's best to let
it stick into your hand, instead of trying to smack it down, and
failing and giving the opponents a chance to catch the disc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimate Rob &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ultimaterob.com/2012/08/02/catch-the-d/"&gt;feels&lt;/a&gt; the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>defense</category><category>catch</category><category>sky</category><category>D</category><category>tips</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/catch-your-ds.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 01:52:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Force Backhand</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/force-backhand.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I need to practice forcing backhand, since we don't do it too often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, our team forces flick/forehand, because it's a harder
throw (for beginners) than the backhand throw.  But, advanced players
usually seem to have as good a forehand flick, if not better, than the
backhand.  We were practicing forcing backhand, yesterday.  As
expected, our marks were not as good as they were, when we were
forcing forehand.  I was marking on the wrong side on a couple of
occasions, and the mess-up lead to our opposition scoring, pretty
easily. But, surprisingly, even our opposition seemed not ready to be
forced backhand and took a while to adjust to the mark!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I realized it helps a lot to remind myself what the mark is,
at the start of every point, and to translate that to, me facing
home/away.  Since the flick is a quicker throw than the backhand, when
forcing backhand, we should be standing a little more towards the
break-side than we would be if we were forcing flick -- our right
shoulder in line with their right shoulder (assuming the thrower is
right-handed).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>force</category><category>mark</category><category>defense</category><category>strategy</category><category>tips</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/force-backhand.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 15:54:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>