<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (disc)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Carry a Disc, Always</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/carry-a-disc-always.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you are living in an Indian city, finding a field to play is a big deal.
A real big deal. It hurts to not have your disc with you, when you have access
to a lush green field, but don't have a disc to play with!  Always carry it!
[If you care about your clothes, carry a pair of shorts and T too!]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more serious note, coaches encourage new players to carry around discs to
get used to the disc in the hand [This is why you see kids dribbling their
basketballs everywhere, not just because it looks hip]. But don't just carry
it, squeeze in a few minutes of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Practice_(learning_method)#Deliberate_practice"&gt;deliberate practice&lt;/a&gt;, if you can, everyday --
something tiny, like switching grips quickly, without using your non-throwing
hand, work on your accuracy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>disc</category><category>tips</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/carry-a-disc-always.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 02:46:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>If you touch it, you should catch it.</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/if-you-touch-it-you-should-catch-it.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a random post on getting better at catching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday's game: Light vs. Dark.  Score-line: 2-11 &amp;amp; 2-4.  A very
lopsided game.  For the record, I was in the light/white team.  What
went wrong?  A lot of things, we were getting a lot of our basics
wrong and the opposition was capitalizing on every small mistake we
made.  We were getting broken, left, right and center; Getting beaten
on the open side; and worst of all dropping simple catches -- unforced
turnovers!  I'm guilty of a couple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the opposition was running hard in D and putting a lot of
pressure on us, but most of the catches that were dropped, seemed to
me like the players were thinking of where they'll put the disc next,
even before they got the disc in their hands.  Like they say, you
should be watching the disc into your hands, while catching it.  Set
yourself, look around and put it, where you want to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the things, I think would help avoid silly drops --&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch the disc into your hands, and catch it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't begin to think of your throw, before the catch.  Worse, don't
let yourself think about the fight you had with your boyfriend on
the previous night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get comfortable with having the disc in your hands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even if you are just a cutter, develop a reasonable arsenal of
throws, so you feel more comfortable getting the disc into your
hands and passing it onto the handler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lot more tips in this issue of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.the-huddle.org/issues/8/anticipation-and-focus/"&gt;the huddle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If you touch it, you should catch it." -- Bill Burruss&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>catch</category><category>disc</category><category>advice</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/if-you-touch-it-you-should-catch-it.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 03:05:03 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>