<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (drill)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Zen Throwing Routine</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/zen-throwing-routine.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another video, by Ultimate Rob, showing the Zen throwing routine
developed by Ben Wiggins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="425" height="344" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/IKPrvgBeZWU?rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;A pdf document for the routine, is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bit.ly/zenthrowing"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drill</category><category>practice</category><category>zen</category><category>throw</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/zen-throwing-routine.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 17:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kung fu Throwing</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/kung-fu-throwing.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimate Rob recently made a nice video of the popular Kung-Fu Throwing
routine.  Just resharing it here, for those who haven't seen it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="425" height="344" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/5mGmnqaN3Wk?rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;An interesting &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kung_fu_(term)"&gt;trivia&lt;/a&gt; :
Kung-fu, in Chinese actually refers to any study, learning, or practice that
requires patience, energy, and time to complete. Ultimate Rob seems to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ultimaterob.com/2013/08/14/kung-fu-throwing-video-walkthrough/"&gt;agree&lt;/a&gt;.
Kung-fu throwing anyone? @pankaj, @voodoo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pdf document for the routine, is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bit.ly/kungfuthrowing"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>kung-fu</category><category>practice</category><category>drill</category><category>throw</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/kung-fu-throwing.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A fun drill</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/a-fun-drill.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/pankajp"&gt;Pankaj&lt;/a&gt; and I came up with a fun throwing and
catching drill, while just fooling around with a couple of discs.  Neither of
us are very experienced players, and nor was this drill scientifically
designed.  We just stumbled upon it, but it seems like it'll help improve a
few things in our game.  Read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="requirements"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a couple of discs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some place where you can throw the disc around (10-15 yards X 4-6 yards,
atleast)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yourself and a partner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the desire to have some fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-does-it-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You and your partner stand about 5 yards apart, or any distance at which you
want to improve your throwing/catching.  You start with one person, throwing a
backhand and the other person flicking forehand.  Both of you throw the disc
at the same time, and try to throw so that the discs collide mid-air, and then
try to catch the disc your partner has thrown at you. Once you catch the disc,
throw it back, as quickly as possible.  After a few throws, you switch the
throwing side (forehand-backhand). Repeat for as long as you are having fun!
I never tried it, but trying it with hammers might be super-fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="benefits-of-the-drill"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Benefits of the drill&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By trying to get the two discs to collide, you try to consistently get your
disc to travel along the same trajectory, effectively trying to repeat the
same throw. The consistency of your throws improves, given that you have
already got your basic technique right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With your partner and yourself throwing discs at the same time, this drill
hopefully helps you get rid of the habit of watching your own throws. You
could possibly improvise and modify the drill a little to get each other to
take a few steps in a specific direction, to get used to moving your feet
immediately after releasing the disc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since you are quickly throwing and releasing, you don't really have much
time to "think" about your throwing or catching.  Once you have done enough
of other drills to get a proper catching or throwing technique, this drill
will help you do it subconsciously, instead of thinking about getting it
right. I find this quite helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also, trying to catch the disc after it hits the disc that you threw,
hopefully teaches you to react quickly, and get used to catching wobbly
discs that have been knocked around by your defenders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, this drill is a lot more fun, than other throwing and catching
drills, I've been introduced to, until now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>throw</category><category>catch</category><category>drill</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/a-fun-drill.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ultimate Practice</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/ultimate-practice.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I came across &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.indiaultimate.org/2013/08/ultimate-practice/"&gt;this nicely written post&lt;/a&gt; on the importance of practice
sessions for a team.  Many of the points discussed are very common in
discussions of our team, and possibly most other Ultimate teams, but it's nice
to read it all at once place, written clearly and convincingly. It also comes
with some interesting and inspiring videos!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throws: Every practice session should start with a lot of throwing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drills: do them as if your life depended on them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fitness: Work on it yourself and with your team; Work on everything - speed,
agility, power, strength&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategy: Try out a lot of things.  Keep learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play: There's no substitute to actual game time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>practice</category><category>throw</category><category>catch</category><category>drill</category><category>fitness</category><category>strategy</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/ultimate-practice.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 18:46:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>