<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (fun)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Surat Ultimate Open 2013, Again!</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/surat-ultimate-open-2013-again.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surat Ultimate Open is here again!  For the second time in 2013,
Fountainhead School is going to host a tournament.  Delhi and Surat
swapped spots on the calendar, due to some issues with organizing the
Delhi tournament in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last tournament in March 2013 was super fun, with good
accommodation and awesome food arranged by the school, along with
amazing fields to play on and lots of teams!  Look at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/213979788772971/"&gt;this facebook
event&lt;/a&gt; for more
details on the upcoming tournament.  See you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I'm back to writing here, after a break of about a month!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>surat</category><category>tournament</category><category>fun</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/surat-ultimate-open-2013-again.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 09:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chennai Heat</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/chennai-heat.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chennaiheat.com"&gt;Chennai Heat&lt;/a&gt; is coming soon! Oct 4 - 6,
Elliots Beach, Besant Nagar, Chennai!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tournament is going to be super fun, with lots of play under lights. There
are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chennaiheat.com/event-info.html"&gt;no games between 9am to 4pm&lt;/a&gt;.  I'm interested to see, what
the teams end up doing during that period. Lot more strategizing?  Or just
hitting the streets of Chennai and binging on Sambar? ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the players (the ones I've played with, and new ones that I'll be
playing with and against), I'm looking forward to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chennaiheat.com/advice.html"&gt;meeting the folks from Quad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>tournament</category><category>chennai</category><category>beach</category><category>fun</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/chennai-heat.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spirit(n) /ˈspirit/: the keystone of Ultimate</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/spiritn-spirit-the-keystone-of-ultimate.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spirit of the Game (SOTG) is rule #1 of the game.  Ultimate relies on
a Spirit of the Game that places the responsibility of fair play on
every player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike any other sport, Ultimate is self refreed at the highest levels
of the game, and this demands a strong sense of sportsmanship and
responsibility from each one of the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the intensity of the game, and the joy it brings to see the
disc speed down the field and being grabbed from the air by a soaring
player, the spirit with which the game is played is one of the things
I love about the game.  I've been lucky to have been associated with a
club that respects the SOTG and has been consistently recognized for
that, in various tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spirit of the game is not about not calling fouls.  It's not about
playing a less intense game, and to give away some easy plays to your
opponent.  The spirit is about respect - respect for the sport, the
rules, your opponent and yourself.  The spirit is about mental
toughness, and integrity.  It's about being consistent on your calls,
no matter what the score line reads.  It's about courage, and
character.  Enough said.  The spirit, will mean different things to
different people.  But it's something that makes me proud of being an
Ultimate player.  It is what brings joy, to all the intensity in the
game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike other sports, the spirit (of sportsmanship) is not a
guideline.  It's in the rule book, and is the #1 rule.  I think, this
is a very important thing to be taught to the new players, specially
those coming from other sports, where bending the rules when nobody
is watching is an accepted part of the culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a recent tournament, I had the chance to be a part of post-game
spirit circles, where teams discuss each others' game including how to
better adhere to the SOTG.  It's a very special experience and nothing
like anything I've been a part of before.  I've had goosebumps, just
watching the spirit circles of some of the other games!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough said.  Now, go read the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wfdf.org/sports/rules-of-play/doc_download/20-rules-of-ultimate"&gt;WFDF Rule&lt;/a&gt; #1.  And &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.the-huddle.org/issues/24/"&gt;this edition&lt;/a&gt; of
Huddle, for more on what some great Ultimate players think about the
Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>spirit</category><category>joy</category><category>rules</category><category>fun</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/spiritn-spirit-the-keystone-of-ultimate.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 15:24:20 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>