<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (game)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Targetted sessions</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/targetted-sessions.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;First things first, the new season begins tomorrow! Yay! I've really had
enough of off-season for this season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This season, every game, I'm going to go with one thing that I want to work on
for each of offense and defense.  I'm going to stick with it, for as long as I
need to.  Until, I'm satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defense: Mark better.  Move my feet more than what I do.  Be on the move,
while on the mark, rather than stand and lean over.  I'll keep posting on
things I discover, and try to make it "measurable".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offense: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ultimaterob.com/2013/08/22/just-catch/"&gt;"Just catch!"&lt;/a&gt;.
I'm going to get more natural while catching, and not get very conscious about
the mechanics.  I think the mechanics need to be fixed during practice, but in
the game, I need to just catch!  Focus on attacking the disc, and getting it
before your opponent or before it hits the ground.  Simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a good season, folks!  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>practice</category><category>improve</category><category>game</category><category>goals</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/targetted-sessions.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 18:29:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Opponents, SOTG &amp; Greatness</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/opponents-greatness.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I came across this quote in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.the-huddle.org/issues/24/what-goes-through-your-head/"&gt;an article on the huddle&lt;/a&gt; and just wanted to
archive it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
The best players treat competition as an opportunity for them to measure
their greatness. Imagine a set of scales: you and your team are on one
end, your opponents on the other. The fulcrum is made of the rules of the
game. If you break the rules, you unbalance the scales and lose the
accuracy of the measurement. If you belittle your opponents, you lose your
counterweight, and diminish the meaning of any success you might have.
(Your win doesn't mean very much if "they suck.") In order to evaluate
yourself and your team honestly—that is, to have self-respect—you have to
treat your opponents and the rules with respect, and even gratitude.
Without them, you can't measure your greatness.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>spirit</category><category>opponents</category><category>game</category><category>quote</category><category>greatness</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/opponents-greatness.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 06:39:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>