<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (joy)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Introducing Ultimate</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/introducing-ultimate.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.barcampmumbai.org/index.php/BCM12#Sessions"&gt;barcamp&lt;/a&gt; next weekend, that I want to talk at, about
Ultimate.  I've, thankfully, been introduced to Ultimate through a
bunch of friends, and playing it.  Then I came into contact with a
wonderful team, who were extremely patient with me...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder what to talk about, at the barcamp.  I want to do justice to
these folks, and not ruin the game for them!  Any ideas on how to go
about, would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>beginners</category><category>talk</category><category>introduce</category><category>spirit</category><category>joy</category><category>noob-friendly</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/introducing-ultimate.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spirit Infected</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/spirit-infected.html</link><dc:creator>voodoo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been playing ultimate once in a while. Or atleast I thought I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single day watching the folks play at the Juhu beach in Mumbai
convinced me that I was as good as someone who never played
before. All I ever did was throw the disc without a technique,
catch it without a technique, run around without a strategy and
hoped to score. I have practiced with them just a couple of
times, played with them a couple of games and I can say that the
experience has been thrilling. I knew the basic rules of the game
and loved it from the moment I heard of it. But there was a joy
in watching people play in the manner in which they were. Clearly
trying to improve, with a lot of intensity and yet enjoying every
bit of it. Most of all it is the people I have met, that have me
excited about the prospect of playing this game. The way they are
accomodating to new comers is something which I have not
experienced earlier. I already knew Punch, who introduced me to
this wonderful group and has also been helping me fix my
throws. On my first day, Pixie helped me with the throws, Sheryl
encouraged me to wait after I got the disc and make better
throws, and Chirag introduced the vertical stack to me. Though I
got a theoretical hang of it, I messed up big time in the game. I
did not touch the disc for the entire period of play. It was
totally due to my badly timed cuts. On my second day, I met
Ganesh. He amazed me with his patience. There was whole bunch of
new comers that day and he patiently took us aside to help us. He
spent a lot his energy in trying to help us improve. This was an
absolutely wonderful experience. He was critical and encouraging
at the same time, pointing out the flaws in what we were doing
and helping us correct them. I learned more Ultimate in that one
hour with Ganesh than all my previous trysts with it. His
enthusiasm was infectious. I now look up to Ganesh and the other
folks. I want to practice more, improve myself, play better, get
fitter, play harder and hopefully imbibe a little of their
spirit. Maybe they just made me want to stick around in Mumbai
for a little longer than I had planned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>noob-friendly</category><category>spirit</category><category>joy</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/spirit-infected.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 13:10:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spirit(n) /ˈspirit/: the keystone of Ultimate</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/spiritn-spirit-the-keystone-of-ultimate.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spirit of the Game (SOTG) is rule #1 of the game.  Ultimate relies on
a Spirit of the Game that places the responsibility of fair play on
every player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike any other sport, Ultimate is self refreed at the highest levels
of the game, and this demands a strong sense of sportsmanship and
responsibility from each one of the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the intensity of the game, and the joy it brings to see the
disc speed down the field and being grabbed from the air by a soaring
player, the spirit with which the game is played is one of the things
I love about the game.  I've been lucky to have been associated with a
club that respects the SOTG and has been consistently recognized for
that, in various tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spirit of the game is not about not calling fouls.  It's not about
playing a less intense game, and to give away some easy plays to your
opponent.  The spirit is about respect - respect for the sport, the
rules, your opponent and yourself.  The spirit is about mental
toughness, and integrity.  It's about being consistent on your calls,
no matter what the score line reads.  It's about courage, and
character.  Enough said.  The spirit, will mean different things to
different people.  But it's something that makes me proud of being an
Ultimate player.  It is what brings joy, to all the intensity in the
game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike other sports, the spirit (of sportsmanship) is not a
guideline.  It's in the rule book, and is the #1 rule.  I think, this
is a very important thing to be taught to the new players, specially
those coming from other sports, where bending the rules when nobody
is watching is an accepted part of the culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a recent tournament, I had the chance to be a part of post-game
spirit circles, where teams discuss each others' game including how to
better adhere to the SOTG.  It's a very special experience and nothing
like anything I've been a part of before.  I've had goosebumps, just
watching the spirit circles of some of the other games!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough said.  Now, go read the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wfdf.org/sports/rules-of-play/doc_download/20-rules-of-ultimate"&gt;WFDF Rule&lt;/a&gt; #1.  And &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.the-huddle.org/issues/24/"&gt;this edition&lt;/a&gt; of
Huddle, for more on what some great Ultimate players think about the
Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>spirit</category><category>joy</category><category>rules</category><category>fun</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/spiritn-spirit-the-keystone-of-ultimate.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 15:24:20 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>