<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (position)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Marking: Positioning and Distance</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/marking-positioning-and-distance.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;During Hyderabad HAT, I was in the cup for most part and learnt a few
things about marking.  My marking improved slightly during the
tournament, and all it needed was changing a couple of simple things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="distance-from-the-handler"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Distance from the handler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was getting broken left, right and center on zone offense.  I know
that I don't move as quickly as I should, to prevent a dump to the
handler on the break side.  But, thanks to help from Vrajesh, I
realized it's not all about speed.  I was getting broken too easily,
because I'd stand too close to the handler and stepping around me was
very easy.  Standing back a couple of steps, helped me.  I was
struggling with this initially, but Vrajesh helped me with this on the
side lines, asking me to step back a little, each time he saw me
stepping too close, and soon I was able to judge the distance myself
and adjust.  Stepping back made it harder for the handler to step
around me and dump, leading to far fewer breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="running-to-your-wo-man-handler"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Running to your (wo)man (handler)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it's a pull, and you are running
down from the other end-zone, it helps if you run down on the break
side, instead of running straight up.  Position yourself a little on
the breakside, so that you don't give away easy break side throws.  If
you are in a cup (or even otherwise), when you run to your (wo)man
(from the force side), don't slow down as soon you reach within the
marking range (3 yards) of your (wo)man. Start slowing down, only once
you cross your man and get to the break side a little and try to stop
as quickly as possible.  That way you are disallowing any easy
breakside throws, just by getting in the way of the throw, even if you
are in no position to "really mark".  Then move in, and position
yourself at the appropriate distance, angle and what not...  Look at
the image below to see, what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/marking.png" src="http://blog.ultimatesport.in/images/marking.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>position</category><category>defense</category><category>tips</category><category>mark</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/marking-positioning-and-distance.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>