<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (spirit)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Rule of the Week: Spirit of the Game</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/rule-of-the-week-spirit-of-the-game.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm going to post one rule a week, starting this week, and this should
ensure at least one post a week up to Feb, '14!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also going to post the official interpretations of the rules, from
the WFDF interpretation guide that complements the rule book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WFDF interpretation guide also mentions the general principles on
which the rules of Ultimate are based.  It would definitely help
players to be aware of these principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="general-principles-for-the-rules-of-ultimate-from-wfdf-interpretations"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General Principles for the Rules of Ultimate (from WFDF interpretations)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rules of Ultimate are based on principles that outline how the
game should be played and how to resolve issues. When encountering a
scenario that is not expressly described by the rules, these
principles are a good guide to help resolve the issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is trusted that no player will intentionally violate the rules;
thus there are no harsh penalties for breaches, but rather a method
for resuming play in a manner which simulates what would most likely
have occurred had there been no breach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A team should not be disadvantaged because the opposition has made
an error or caused a breach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calls should only be made where a breach has occurred that has a
meaningful impact on the game. Players should allow for a reasonable
degree of tolerance for minor breaches involving small discrepancies
in distance and time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not everybody sees a situation in the same light. Two players with a
very good view of a situation can still see very different things
happening. Human perception is not perfect. Players should be aware
of this when trying to resolve calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a call cannot be resolved then the disc shall be returned to
where possession was last undisputed and play shall resume as it was
prior to the call.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rule-1-spirit-of-the-game"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rule #1: Spirit of the Game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultimate is a non-contact, self-refereed sport. All players are
responsible for administering and adhering to the rules. Ultimate
relies upon a Spirit of the Game that places the responsibility for
fair play on every player.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is trusted that no player will intentionally break the rules;
thus there are no harsh penalties for breaches, but rather a method
for resuming play in a manner which simulates what would most
likely have occurred had there been no breach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players should be mindful of the fact that they are acting as
referees in any arbitration between teams. Players must:&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;know the rules;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be fair-minded and objective;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be truthful;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explain their viewpoint clearly and briefly;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allow opponents a reasonable chance to speak;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;resolve disputes as quickly as possible, using respectful
language;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make calls in a consistent manner throughout the game;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only make a call where a breach is significant enough to make a
difference to the outcome of the action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highly competitive play is encouraged, but should never sacrifice
the mutual respect between players, adherence to the agreed-upon
rules of the game, or the basic joy of play.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The following actions are examples of good spirit:&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;informing a team-mate if they have made a wrong or unnecessary
call or caused a foul or violation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;retracting a call when you no longer believe the call was
necessary;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;complimenting an opponent for good play or spirit;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;introducing yourself to your opponent; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reacting calmly towards disagreement or provocation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The following actions are clear violations of the spirit of the
game and must be avoided by all participants:&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dangerous play and aggressive behaviour;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intentional fouling or other intentional rule violations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taunting or intimidating opposing players;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disrespectful celebration after scoring;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making calls in retaliation to an opponent’s call; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;calling for a pass from an opposition player.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teams are guardians of the Spirit of the Game, and must:&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take responsibility for teaching their players the rules and
good spirit;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discipline players who display poor spirit; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide constructive feedback to other teams about how to
improve their adherence to the Spirit of the Game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the case where a novice player commits an infraction out of
ignorance of the rules, experienced players are obliged to explain
the infraction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An experienced player, who offers advice on rules and guides
on-field arbitration, may supervise games involving beginners or
younger players.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rules should be interpreted by the players directly involved in the
play, or by players who had the best perspective on the
play. Non-players, apart from the captain, should refrain from
getting involved. However players may seek the perspective of
non-players to clarify the rules, and to assist players to make the
appropriate call for "down" calls and line calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players and captains are solely responsible for making all calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If, after discussion, players cannot agree what occurred in a play,
the disc shall be returned to the last non-disputed thrower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="interpretations"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interpretations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Providing evidence to support a call (1.3.4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;What&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;It is an essential component of good spirit that a player must
be prepared, if asked, to explain concisely the objective
evidence that led to making a call, or contesting a call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Example&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;After making a travel call, if asked, the defender might explain
"I saw you lift your pivot foot while the disc was still in your
hand."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Why&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;The objective evidence is evidence that can be tested for
validity. It makes it clear that the call was not based on
emotion or what the player wanted or expected to happen, but what
they actually observed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;If a player is not reasonably certain of the objective evidence,
they should not make a call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Extra&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Players should be aware and understanding of the language
limitations accompanying international play, however opponents
should still be able to communicate, even through gestures, what
they saw. Team captains and team mates should get involved if
they think their team’s player is wrong or does not behave
correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Making calls in a consistent manner throughout the game (1.3.7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;What&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Players should make calls without taking into account the
context of the game. This means that players should not start
making more calls just because the game is nearly over and the
scores are quite close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Example&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;If at the start of the game minor travel infractions were not
called, then they should not be called later in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Only calling significant breaches (1.3.8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;What&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Players should allow for a reasonable degree of tolerance for
minor breaches involving small discrepancies in distance and
time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Example&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;If the thrower established a pivot one centimetre away from the
correct pivot point then a travel infraction should not be called.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Disrespectful celebration after scoring (1.6.4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;What&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;This includes spiking directed at an opponent and taunting of the
opponent by "showing" them the disc. These actions must be
avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Result&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Opposing team captains should discuss all matters relating to
violations of spirit and try to resolve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Seeking perspective from non players (1.10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Note&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;It is still up to the players involved to make the final
call. Non players must not provide verbal advice regarding a call
unless they are requested to by the players involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Line calls are defined as any call relating to the spot that the
disc became or went out-of-bounds, or a player's position
relative to the perimeter lines or goal line. Line calls relate
to the following calls: "out-of-bounds", "goal" and "offside".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Discussion of what occurred in a play (1.12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Note&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Before the disc is returned to the thrower when players cannot
agree, players should discuss what happened in the play. Both
players involved should attempt to clearly explain what they
think happened and listen to the view of their opponent, or other
players with good perspective on the play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If discussion is difficult due to a language barrier, then
gestures or recreations of the incident can be used to indicate
what was experienced during the incident (eg. striking yourself
across the back of the hand to show that your hand was hit as you
were trying to catch the disc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;The discussion should be as brief as possible with the preferred
outcome being either a retracted call, or an uncontested
call. However once it becomes clear that no resolution will be
reached, the disc should be returned to the last non- disputed
thrower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="spirit-of-the-game-stoppage-appendix-9"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spirit of the Game Stoppage (Appendix 9)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a team's captain believes that either or both teams are failing
to follow the Spirit of the Game (SOTG), they may call a "Spirit of
the Game Stoppage". This can only be called:&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After a call which stops the play or any other stoppage, prior
to the disc being checked in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the start of a point and prior to the ensuing pull.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During this stoppage, neither team may engage in tactical
discussions. All team members of both teams will form a "spirit
circle" in the middle of the field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separately from the spirit circle, the two opposing team captains
shall discuss all current issues with adherence to SOTG, determine
actions to rectify those issues, and then convey the agreement to
the spirit circle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SOTG stoppages do not affect, nor are they affected by, the number
of time-outs available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time taken for a SOTG Stoppage will be added to the game time to
determine time caps for the game. The captain initiating the
Stoppage will convey the start and end of the Stoppage to game
officials for time-keeping purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional Reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.the-huddle.org/issues/24/"&gt;Huddle Issue #24&lt;/a&gt; Top
players from around the world, write about their views on SOTG.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://wfdf.org/about/meeting-minutes/doc_download/62-history-of-the-spirit-of-the-game-and-observers-in-the-sport-of-ultimate"&gt;History of SOTG and observers in the game [pdf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>rules</category><category>spirit</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/rule-of-the-week-spirit-of-the-game.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ultimate 101 (video)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/ultimate-101-video.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just stumbled upon this short, and sweet video.  I'm probably going to
show this as a part of my talk at the Barcamp on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="425" height="344" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/NhTHzkWoB6A?rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>ultimate</category><category>rules</category><category>spirit</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/ultimate-101-video.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 18:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Introducing Ultimate</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/introducing-ultimate.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.barcampmumbai.org/index.php/BCM12#Sessions"&gt;barcamp&lt;/a&gt; next weekend, that I want to talk at, about
Ultimate.  I've, thankfully, been introduced to Ultimate through a
bunch of friends, and playing it.  Then I came into contact with a
wonderful team, who were extremely patient with me...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder what to talk about, at the barcamp.  I want to do justice to
these folks, and not ruin the game for them!  Any ideas on how to go
about, would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>beginners</category><category>talk</category><category>introduce</category><category>spirit</category><category>joy</category><category>noob-friendly</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/introducing-ultimate.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Opponents, SOTG &amp; Greatness</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/opponents-greatness.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I came across this quote in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.the-huddle.org/issues/24/what-goes-through-your-head/"&gt;an article on the huddle&lt;/a&gt; and just wanted to
archive it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
The best players treat competition as an opportunity for them to measure
their greatness. Imagine a set of scales: you and your team are on one
end, your opponents on the other. The fulcrum is made of the rules of the
game. If you break the rules, you unbalance the scales and lose the
accuracy of the measurement. If you belittle your opponents, you lose your
counterweight, and diminish the meaning of any success you might have.
(Your win doesn't mean very much if "they suck.") In order to evaluate
yourself and your team honestly—that is, to have self-respect—you have to
treat your opponents and the rules with respect, and even gratitude.
Without them, you can't measure your greatness.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>spirit</category><category>opponents</category><category>game</category><category>quote</category><category>greatness</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/opponents-greatness.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 06:39:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spirit Infected</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/spirit-infected.html</link><dc:creator>voodoo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been playing ultimate once in a while. Or atleast I thought I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single day watching the folks play at the Juhu beach in Mumbai
convinced me that I was as good as someone who never played
before. All I ever did was throw the disc without a technique,
catch it without a technique, run around without a strategy and
hoped to score. I have practiced with them just a couple of
times, played with them a couple of games and I can say that the
experience has been thrilling. I knew the basic rules of the game
and loved it from the moment I heard of it. But there was a joy
in watching people play in the manner in which they were. Clearly
trying to improve, with a lot of intensity and yet enjoying every
bit of it. Most of all it is the people I have met, that have me
excited about the prospect of playing this game. The way they are
accomodating to new comers is something which I have not
experienced earlier. I already knew Punch, who introduced me to
this wonderful group and has also been helping me fix my
throws. On my first day, Pixie helped me with the throws, Sheryl
encouraged me to wait after I got the disc and make better
throws, and Chirag introduced the vertical stack to me. Though I
got a theoretical hang of it, I messed up big time in the game. I
did not touch the disc for the entire period of play. It was
totally due to my badly timed cuts. On my second day, I met
Ganesh. He amazed me with his patience. There was whole bunch of
new comers that day and he patiently took us aside to help us. He
spent a lot his energy in trying to help us improve. This was an
absolutely wonderful experience. He was critical and encouraging
at the same time, pointing out the flaws in what we were doing
and helping us correct them. I learned more Ultimate in that one
hour with Ganesh than all my previous trysts with it. His
enthusiasm was infectious. I now look up to Ganesh and the other
folks. I want to practice more, improve myself, play better, get
fitter, play harder and hopefully imbibe a little of their
spirit. Maybe they just made me want to stick around in Mumbai
for a little longer than I had planned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>noob-friendly</category><category>spirit</category><category>joy</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/spirit-infected.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 13:10:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spirit(n) /ˈspirit/: the keystone of Ultimate</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/spiritn-spirit-the-keystone-of-ultimate.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spirit of the Game (SOTG) is rule #1 of the game.  Ultimate relies on
a Spirit of the Game that places the responsibility of fair play on
every player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike any other sport, Ultimate is self refreed at the highest levels
of the game, and this demands a strong sense of sportsmanship and
responsibility from each one of the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the intensity of the game, and the joy it brings to see the
disc speed down the field and being grabbed from the air by a soaring
player, the spirit with which the game is played is one of the things
I love about the game.  I've been lucky to have been associated with a
club that respects the SOTG and has been consistently recognized for
that, in various tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spirit of the game is not about not calling fouls.  It's not about
playing a less intense game, and to give away some easy plays to your
opponent.  The spirit is about respect - respect for the sport, the
rules, your opponent and yourself.  The spirit is about mental
toughness, and integrity.  It's about being consistent on your calls,
no matter what the score line reads.  It's about courage, and
character.  Enough said.  The spirit, will mean different things to
different people.  But it's something that makes me proud of being an
Ultimate player.  It is what brings joy, to all the intensity in the
game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike other sports, the spirit (of sportsmanship) is not a
guideline.  It's in the rule book, and is the #1 rule.  I think, this
is a very important thing to be taught to the new players, specially
those coming from other sports, where bending the rules when nobody
is watching is an accepted part of the culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a recent tournament, I had the chance to be a part of post-game
spirit circles, where teams discuss each others' game including how to
better adhere to the SOTG.  It's a very special experience and nothing
like anything I've been a part of before.  I've had goosebumps, just
watching the spirit circles of some of the other games!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough said.  Now, go read the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wfdf.org/sports/rules-of-play/doc_download/20-rules-of-ultimate"&gt;WFDF Rule&lt;/a&gt; #1.  And &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.the-huddle.org/issues/24/"&gt;this edition&lt;/a&gt; of
Huddle, for more on what some great Ultimate players think about the
Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>spirit</category><category>joy</category><category>rules</category><category>fun</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/spiritn-spirit-the-keystone-of-ultimate.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 15:24:20 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>