<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (team)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Just Show Up!</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/just-show-up.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Where the @#@#@ is your commitment?" -- our captain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be a top player, a top team, you have no other option
but to practice as hard, with as much commitment as you can.  There's
no two ways about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you are the only one in a practice session, it doesn't matter.
There are surely things, that you can work on your own upon.  Show up
and Practice hard!  Set yourself &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.indiaultimate.org/2013/09/it-doesnt-have-to-be-fun-to-be-fun/"&gt;goals&lt;/a&gt;,
and work towards them.  Make yourself a training routine.  Do whatever
it takes, to get better as an individual player, and as a team!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>practice</category><category>player</category><category>top</category><category>team</category><category>commitment</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/just-show-up.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Recover quick!</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/recover-quick.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quarter finals, Bangalore: We barely made into, and were elated about being
in. Its the first half and we catch-up to 4-5 after we were trailing by a
bigger margin. After some good defense, we are on O, and we make some nice
moves to move up to the end zone, and I ask for a disc that I didn't really
have. A man is on me, but the disc reaches before him, and I put it down, in
the endzone!  The game went on; my team wasn't mad at me and continued playing
hard, but we lost the game 8-9.  The catch was a crucial one, that I think
cost us the game.  I sat out for most of the rest of the game.  Others covered
for me, even when we had a really tiny squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody makes mistakes.  Great players, included.  But, what makes them
great is that they put their mistakes behind them very quickly, atleast in the
short term and move on.  I think I've seen some of the players, even let their
mistakes push them into "the zone", performing a few notches above what they
were, before they made that silly drop or made that wild throw.  Like its
important to recover physically, in as short time as possible to be a good
player/athlete (we can talk about that in another post, someday), its also
important to atleast get over your mistakes in the short term (if not be
motivated, by them) and continue to play for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Son, you dropped a simple catch?  This is your chance for that psycho layout
D!  Err, but recoverr...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of interesting blog posts by Jason, on this topic: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ultimaterob.com/2012/09/06/ultimate-intelligence-the-good-mistakes/"&gt;Good Mistakes&lt;/a&gt;
, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ultimaterob.com/2013/01/23/ultimate-intelligence-its-not-about-you/"&gt;It's not about you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mental-game</category><category>recovery</category><category>team</category><category>advice</category><category>mistake</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/recover-quick.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 18:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>