<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ultimate! (violation)</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 22:00:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>What is a Pick?</title><link>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/what-is-a-pick.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A "pick" is a violation in Ultimate, that is called by a defender when he is
screened from getting to the disc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A screen, in general, is a blocking move by an offensive player to
block or obstruct the movement of a defender, to free a teammate to
shoot, receive a pass, or drive in to score. In basketball, it is also
known as a pick.  While this is allowed and commonly used in sports
like basketball, a defender in Ultimate can call a Pick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From #18.3 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wfdf.org/sports/rules-of-play/doc_download/20-rules-of-ultimate"&gt;WFDF Rules&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a defensive player is guarding an offensive player and they are
prevented from moving towards/with that player by another player,
that defensive player may call "Pick"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once play has stopped, the obstructed player may move to the agreed
position they would have otherwise occupied if the obstruction had
not occurred. The disc is returned to the thrower (if the disc was
thrown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wfdf.org/sports/rules-of-play/doc_download/23-official-interpretations-"&gt;official interpretation&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pick should only be called if the obstructed player is within 3
metres of the player they were guarding at the time they were
obstructed. However they do not need to be less than 3 metres away
at the time of the call because the obstruction may cause this
distance to quickly grow before the call can be made.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pick cannot be called by the offense.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pick should not be called by a defender who was obstructed while
attempting to make a play on the disc, that is not related to their
ability to move towards/with the player they are guarding (however a
defender may call a violation under Rule 12.7 if applicable).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Ultimate, a player calls a Violation, by either calling "Violation"
or the specific name of the violation, "Pick" in this case.  The
player can also show the hand signal, in the image, when calling a
pick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/pick_signal.jpg" class="align-center" src="http://blog.ultimatesport.in/images/pick_signal.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WFDF has a nice decision diagram illustrating the various scenarios.
I'll not go into explaining them in detail, unless something really
needs to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/pick_decision.jpg" class="align-center" src="http://blog.ultimatesport.in/images/pick_decision.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credits: The images are courtesy WFDF rule books!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>rules</category><category>foul</category><category>violation</category><category>infraction</category><guid>http://blog.ultimatesport.in/posts/what-is-a-pick.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 01:14:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>